[
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Noise pollution refers to unwanted or harmful ________ that disrupts the environment.",
      "options": [
        "water",
        "light",
        "sound",
        "air"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "One of the major sources of noise pollution is ________ traffic.",
      "options": [
        "water",
        "road",
        "foot",
        "space"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Airplanes taking off and landing contribute to noise pollution in areas near ________.",
      "options": [
        "factories",
        "markets",
        "airports",
        "schools"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Construction activities such as ________ and drilling create loud noises.",
      "options": [
        "painting",
        "hammering",
        "sweeping",
        "plastering"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "Factories and power plants generate noise pollution due to ________.",
      "options": [
        "heavy machinery",
        "quiet offices",
        "calm environments",
        "silent generators"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "One of the common household sources of noise pollution is ________.",
      "options": [
        "vacuum cleaner",
        "television",
        "mixer grinder",
        "all of the above"
      ],
      "answer": 4
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Long-term exposure to loud noise can lead to ________ problems.",
      "options": [
        "hearing",
        "digestive",
        "skin",
        "vision"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Noise pollution can cause stress and ________ in humans.",
      "options": [
        "relaxation",
        "happiness",
        "anxiety",
        "sleepiness"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "One way to reduce noise pollution is by planting ________ along roads and buildings.",
      "options": [
        "flowers",
        "trees",
        "grass",
        "moss"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "In Silent Zones, noise levels should not exceed ________ dB during nighttime.",
      "options": [
        "70",
        "55",
        "40",
        "90"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    }
]
  